<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>China&#39;s Economy on 人大国新班 2016 级</title>
    <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinas-economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China&#39;s Economy on 人大国新班 2016 级</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinas-economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathoning Mirrors a Booming Sports &amp; Fitness Industry</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/08/30/marathon-mirrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/08/30/marathon-mirrors/</guid>
      <description>Marathoning hobbyist Du Liyuan nears the finish-lineCourtesy: Du Liyuan
  BEIJING – The official time read 1:43:45. Du Liyuan was excited, since he had just achieved his personal best – and done so in the 2017 Beijing Half Marathon.
For the 27-year-old product manager, this was already his fourth marathon of the year. Yet when Du took up running only two years ago, it wasn’t with such competitive aspirations in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Marketplace Tightens, More Students Drawn To Job Fairs</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/marketplace-tightens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/marketplace-tightens/</guid>
      <description>Job-seekers discuss opportunities with HR staff at Renmin University&amp;#39;s job fairPhoto: Ray Lin
  BEIJING – The biggest-ever job fair, at one of Beijing’s top universities, attracted more than 2,000 job seekers on March 17 — as well as more than 200 recruiters, ranging from manufacturers to Internet companies to government agencies, said the organizer.
“I’ve already submitted three resumes, as I believe the wide net catches more fish,” said Wang Zhijia, who will graduate from Renmin University of China with a degree in economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Students Eye Labor Market, Job Fairs Offer Early Options</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/labor-market/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The biggest-ever job fair of Renmin University of China (RUC), a top university in Beijing, attracted more than 2,000 job seekers on March 17, with more than 200 recruiters, ranging from manufacture to Internet, companies to government agencies, to help graduates in this competitive job-hunting year.
According to the Chinese government, an unprecedented 7.95 million graduate jobhunters will enter the labor market this year, increasing by 300 thousand more than 2016, and the job vacancy amount is growing slowly as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China’s Shared-Economy Bike Boom Tested By Vandalism</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/shared-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/shared-bike/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Tires flat. Chains broken. Seats or pedals missing, as are the shiny new locks. These are the novel features of several Ofo bikes parked in Renmin University of China (RUC) beside the building Zhixing last Tuesday morning.
All are ‘new’ bicycles of ofo – the leading bike sharing platform in China – yet symbolize the rising vandalism that has percolated in RUC amidst a growing popularity of ofo bikes on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Craft Beer: A Sign of China’s Rising Middle Class</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/beer/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – One small coffee shop in China’s capital held a beer tasting party on March 17, attracting dozens of young, white-collar Chinese who wanted to have something special on weekends.
Chen Long, co-founder of Qidian Cafe&amp;amp;Bar and the host of tonight’s fifth weekly salon, opened bottles of beer and passed them round by round while delivering a craft beer introductory presentation.
“Not all the beer tastes like water. The flavor can be strong and colorful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>