<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feminism in China on 人大国新班 2016 级</title>
    <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/feminism-in-china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feminism in China on 人大国新班 2016 级</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>国际新闻课程作业</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/feminism-in-china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Actresses Forced to Quiet the Voice of Vagina Monologues</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/05/vagina-monologues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/05/vagina-monologues/</guid>
      <description>Masturbation, portrayed on stage: One of the play&amp;#39;s more controversial scenes — and a taboo topic in ChinaPhoto: Jennifer Zhang
  BEIJING - The Chinese version of The Vagina Monologues &amp;ndash; entitled &amp;ldquo;She Says&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; was performed by a controversial feminist group on March 25th in Beijing. While the first five scenes went smoothly, during the last scene, the performer was not allowed to use a microphone by some cultural censorship committee, due to sensitivity over the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feminist Banners Calling for Equality Provoke Controversy</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/feminist-banners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/feminist-banners/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – At one of China’s leading universities, two feminist students chose the annual Girls’ Day – which traditionally celebrates the charm of female students and expresses affection for them – to hang banners and provoke an increasingly sensitive debate: about gender equality.
As men conventionally give little gifts, even in hopes of landing a girlfriend, one banner by the two feminist organizers declared that “No Free Gifts from Boys — I Want Free Rights in Employment!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>