<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Relations on 人大国新班 2016 级</title>
    <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/international-relations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Relations on 人大国新班 2016 级</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/international-relations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus Talk: Trump Reflects New Global Political Climate</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-reflects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-reflects/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – A lecture on Donald Trump, China and the World in one of China’s top universities attracted an unexpected large audience this Thursday. It analyzed the increasing complexity of Sino-American relationship after Trump took office and the rise of nativism, populism and nationalism, which would pose great challenges to the world.
“We are now at a turning point,” said Wang Lili, one of the organizers and Deputy Dean of National Academy of Development and Strategy, RUC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Some in China, Trump Highlights A Worrisome Trend</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-highlights/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – U.S. President Donald Trump, tagged as “business man” and “entertainer,” is bound to bring something different to America. With Trump coming into power, though, the relationship between America and China – the world’s two largest economies – will be more unpredictable in the new age, says one top Chinese scholar.
A tiny movement between US and China will have a big impact on global political climate change, said Shi Yinhong, in a March 16th lecture entitled “Trump, China and the World.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>