<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>人大国新班 2016 级</title>
    <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 人大国新班 2016 级</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rucer.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amid Rising HIV, Signs of Progress – Yet Hurdles Remain</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/08/30/amid-rising-hiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/08/30/amid-rising-hiv/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING -– When Liu first heard his devastating diagnosis, the 22-year-old was in a hospital waiting-room, among other Chinese patients.
The nurse practically shouted the news: he was HIV-positive. His heart skipped a beat.
“Yuck,” the nurse sneered at him, as he stood, speechless. “You must have had sex with men.”
Other patients squinted at Liu – a university student who is indeed gay – and whispers filled the room. The doctor forced him to sign a form with his own pen – fearing any physical contact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathoning Mirrors a Booming Sports &amp; Fitness Industry</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/08/30/marathon-mirrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/08/30/marathon-mirrors/</guid>
      <description>Marathoning hobbyist Du Liyuan nears the finish-lineCourtesy: Du Liyuan
  BEIJING – The official time read 1:43:45. Du Liyuan was excited, since he had just achieved his personal best – and done so in the 2017 Beijing Half Marathon.
For the 27-year-old product manager, this was already his fourth marathon of the year. Yet when Du took up running only two years ago, it wasn’t with such competitive aspirations in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actresses Forced to Quiet the Voice of Vagina Monologues</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/05/vagina-monologues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/05/vagina-monologues/</guid>
      <description>Masturbation, portrayed on stage: One of the play&amp;#39;s more controversial scenes — and a taboo topic in ChinaPhoto: Jennifer Zhang
  BEIJING - The Chinese version of The Vagina Monologues &amp;ndash; entitled &amp;ldquo;She Says&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; was performed by a controversial feminist group on March 25th in Beijing. While the first five scenes went smoothly, during the last scene, the performer was not allowed to use a microphone by some cultural censorship committee, due to sensitivity over the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amid Two-Child Policy, Working Women Cite New Negative</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/two-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/two-child/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Female graduates were admitted into a job fair 30 minutes earlier than their male counterparts for the first time on March 14 at Renmin, one of China’s top universities, in order to relieve gender discrimination.
In 2016, China abandoned its 39-year-long one-child policy and allowed two children for all couples. The second largest economy now needs more babies to boost its shrinking workforce and to support the ageing population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Marketplace Tightens, More Students Drawn To Job Fairs</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/marketplace-tightens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/marketplace-tightens/</guid>
      <description>Job-seekers discuss opportunities with HR staff at Renmin University&amp;#39;s job fairPhoto: Ray Lin
  BEIJING – The biggest-ever job fair, at one of Beijing’s top universities, attracted more than 2,000 job seekers on March 17 — as well as more than 200 recruiters, ranging from manufacturers to Internet companies to government agencies, said the organizer.
“I’ve already submitted three resumes, as I believe the wide net catches more fish,” said Wang Zhijia, who will graduate from Renmin University of China with a degree in economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Students Eye Labor Market, Job Fairs Offer Early Options</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/labor-market/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The biggest-ever job fair of Renmin University of China (RUC), a top university in Beijing, attracted more than 2,000 job seekers on March 17, with more than 200 recruiters, ranging from manufacture to Internet, companies to government agencies, to help graduates in this competitive job-hunting year.
According to the Chinese government, an unprecedented 7.95 million graduate jobhunters will enter the labor market this year, increasing by 300 thousand more than 2016, and the job vacancy amount is growing slowly as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus Contest Aims to Reignite Interest in Book-Reading</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/campus-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/campus-contest/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The Student Union of the Science Department of Renmin University of China (RUC) recently launched a serial book-reading contest every two weeks facing all students on campus primarily aimed at reigniting college students’ awareness on reading and in turn increase their own competitiveness for their future career.
This book-reading contest opens a window onto a broader concern within Chinese educational system, that the Chinese are lagging behind their peers by other countries in terms of reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus Talk: Trump Reflects New Global Political Climate</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-reflects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-reflects/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – A lecture on Donald Trump, China and the World in one of China’s top universities attracted an unexpected large audience this Thursday. It analyzed the increasing complexity of Sino-American relationship after Trump took office and the rise of nativism, populism and nationalism, which would pose great challenges to the world.
“We are now at a turning point,” said Wang Lili, one of the organizers and Deputy Dean of National Academy of Development and Strategy, RUC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China’s Shared-Economy Bike Boom Tested By Vandalism</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/shared-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/shared-bike/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Tires flat. Chains broken. Seats or pedals missing, as are the shiny new locks. These are the novel features of several Ofo bikes parked in Renmin University of China (RUC) beside the building Zhixing last Tuesday morning.
All are ‘new’ bicycles of ofo – the leading bike sharing platform in China – yet symbolize the rising vandalism that has percolated in RUC amidst a growing popularity of ofo bikes on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothing Exhibit Stirs Chinese Nostalgia – and Cultural Pride</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/clothing-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/clothing-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>Film-makers asking one staffer to explain the aim of their unique exhibit of handmade Chinese clothesPhoto: Michael Li
  BEIJING – A unique, six-month exhibition on handmade Chinese apparel has gained renewed attention at its last stage, as Figure Video, which specializing in cultural celebrities, started shooting a documentary about it at the Backstreet Art-Museum.
Duan Kun, director of the Figure Video team, said that in an era of mass-produced, machine-made clothing, they were interested in the exhibition’s theme: “Seeking Clothes for Stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feminist Banners Calling for Equality Provoke Controversy</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/feminist-banners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/feminist-banners/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – At one of China’s leading universities, two feminist students chose the annual Girls’ Day – which traditionally celebrates the charm of female students and expresses affection for them – to hang banners and provoke an increasingly sensitive debate: about gender equality.
As men conventionally give little gifts, even in hopes of landing a girlfriend, one banner by the two feminist organizers declared that “No Free Gifts from Boys — I Want Free Rights in Employment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Chinese Youth, Study-Abroad More Than Just Adventure</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/study-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/study-abroad/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Students poured into international office for interview to participate in studying abroad programs Wednesday morning, which has been one of the most popular programs on campus, as the school staff in charge pointed out.
“Experience in a different culture is attractive,” said Lin, a student who just finished interview, “the idea of meeting and talking with a variety of people all over the world also adds to its weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Craft Beer: A Sign of China’s Rising Middle Class</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/beer/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – One small coffee shop in China’s capital held a beer tasting party on March 17, attracting dozens of young, white-collar Chinese who wanted to have something special on weekends.
Chen Long, co-founder of Qidian Cafe&amp;amp;Bar and the host of tonight’s fifth weekly salon, opened bottles of beer and passed them round by round while delivering a craft beer introductory presentation.
“Not all the beer tastes like water. The flavor can be strong and colorful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls’ Day Banners Offer Glimpse of Feminist Awakening</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/girls-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/girls-day/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – March 7, the annual Girls’ Day in China, is traditionally the day when male students state their care or adoration to girls with sugary words on dazzling banners – though, some say for many boys, it’s mere flattery in search of a girlfriend. But this year, some young women at Renmin University of China, at least, chose this occasion to hang some incongruous banners to voice their dissatisfaction with what they see as gender discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters Alive Renews Public Passion for Cultural TV Shows</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/letters-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/letters-alive/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Recently, a “letter reading” TV program called Letters Alive received great popularity and success in China. The director of this program Guan Zhengwen, also a famous producer, gave a lecture to share the secrets behind the huge success of Letters Alive in Renmin University on March 17th.
Letters Alive is a cultural TV program where remarkable letters are read by outstanding performers. Its popularity soared immediately after its first broadcast in Dec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Some in China, Trump Highlights A Worrisome Trend</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/trump-highlights/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – U.S. President Donald Trump, tagged as “business man” and “entertainer,” is bound to bring something different to America. With Trump coming into power, though, the relationship between America and China – the world’s two largest economies – will be more unpredictable in the new age, says one top Chinese scholar.
A tiny movement between US and China will have a big impact on global political climate change, said Shi Yinhong, in a March 16th lecture entitled “Trump, China and the World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universities Urged To Go Green – At Least One Hour Per Year</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/go-green/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/go-green/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – March 25th witnessed China’s 10th annual Earth Hour — an event held to encourage individuals to turn off non-essential electric light for one hour between 8:30 pm to 9:30 pm. The theme for this year is “Turn up the dark.” Colleges in Beijing, however, are not dark at all.
According to China Electricity Council, in 2016, 65.2% of the power generated in China was from firing coal. China, the world’s largest emitter of carbon dioxide, does need such an hour to “cool down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Contest Aims to Boost Appeal of Book-Reading</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-contest/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The Student Union of the Science Department of Renmin University recently launched a serial book-reading contest, which is held every two weeks on Wednesday. This contest primarily aims at fellow science students to raise awareness that reading should not only be a burden in their studies, but can be for fun, too, and may even enhance their creativity and competitiveness in the labor market.
Indeed, the book-reading contest opens a window onto a broader concern within Chinese educational system that students are lagging behind their peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Feminists Call for Equality, Spark Controversy</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-feminists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-feminists/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING - At one of China’s leading universities, two feminist students chose the annual Girls’ Day — which typically sees Chinese men express their affection for women — to hang banners and provoke an increasingly sensitive debate: about gender equality.
As men traditionally give little gifts on Girls’ Day, one banner declared: “No Free Gifts from Boys &amp;ndash; I Want Free Rights in Employment!” One of the organizers, who is unwilling to be identified, said: “The call for gender equality should be heard, especially on Girls’ Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Africans React to Chinalize, Revealing Sensitivities</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/visiting-africans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/visiting-africans/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Use of the term “Chinalize” sparked controversy during a lecture by a Chinese professor for 48 Asian and African journalists in one of China’s leading universities, Renmin.
When asked about how to develop Africa, the professor made up a word “Chinalize”, trying to sell the way of development with Chinese characteristics.
However, this word provoked an online protest from the African audience who refuse to become more like Chinese people in culture and values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Our Course</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Bt Michael J. Jordan, Visiting Professor, Renmin University of China China is not only the world’s most-populous nation, but also the largest English-learning market: some have estimated that 300 million-plus Chinese have taken up the language.
Yet what I believe the world’s second-largest economy truly needs are more Chinese who write well – as a bridge to the outside world, explaining the work of Chinese organizations, companies and government agencies, or describing the lives of ordinary Chinese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First assignment</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/assignment/assignmentone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/assignment/assignmentone/</guid>
      <description>By Michael J. Jordan, Visiting Professor, Renmin University of China Our first course assignment – which generated this batch of stories – was to spotlight any News story on campus.
However, as I instructed the students, do NOT produce your story as if for the campus newspaper – for a local, “insider” audience. Instead, as if for a global news agency, aiming for that “smart, curious, international audience.”
This story teaches the core fundamentals of preparation, fact-gathering, interviewing and effective writing, which, as I told our Student-Journalists, “You’ll need for any career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First assignment</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/assignmentone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/assignmentone/</guid>
      <description>By Michael J. Jordan, Visiting Professor, Renmin University of China Our first course assignment – which generated this batch of stories – was to spotlight any News story on campus.
However, as I instructed the students, do NOT produce your story as if for the campus newspaper – for a local, “insider” audience. Instead, as if for a global news agency, aiming for that “smart, curious, international audience.”
This story teaches the core fundamentals of preparation, fact-gathering, interviewing and effective writing, which, as I told our Student-Journalists, “You’ll need for any career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson Learned</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/lessonlearned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/lessonlearned/</guid>
      <description>Know My Audience Well By Chenwei Fan I was quite confused when Michael asked us to include “Darwinian origins and evolution” of the issue we wanted to cover. We had to spend almost 50% of the article explaining earlier trend of the issue. Shall I call this news writing at all?
After 16 weeks with Michael, I have found the answer to my question. It is all about how to impact my target audience effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson Shared</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/lessonshared/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/lessonshared/</guid>
      <description>By Michael J. Jordan, Visiting Professor, Renmin University of China Beyond my two decades as a Foreign Correspondent, I’ve taught various forms of International Journalism over the past 14 years – on four continents. And the same challenge I faced with this group of Chinese students, I experienced when teaching in New York, or Central Europe, or Southern Africa, or in Hong Kong.
To be fair, imagine yourself in their shoes: they’re young Chinese, living in their homeland, yet trying to portray it accurately as possible, for outsiders – the vast majority of whom have never been to China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second assignment</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/assignment/assignmenttwo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/assignment/assignmenttwo/</guid>
      <description>By Michael J. Jordan, Visiting Professor, Renmin University of China Our second course assignment was an illuminating piece of Foreign Reporting — or, as I also presented it: International Storytelling. From that, we produced this collection of 14 “humanized, fact-based” stories.
A core challenge was to show my young Chinese Student-Journalists how to think – and produce stories – as I would, as a Foreign Correspondent. No small feat, as they’d be doing so from their ownhomeland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second assignment</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/assignmenttwo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/assignmenttwo/</guid>
      <description>By Michael J. Jordan, Visiting Professor, Renmin University of China Our second course assignment was an illuminating piece of Foreign Reporting — or, as I also presented it: International Storytelling. From that, we produced this collection of 14 “humanized, fact-based” stories.
A core challenge was to show my young Chinese Student-Journalists how to think – and produce stories – as I would, as a Foreign Correspondent. No small feat, as they’d be doing so from their ownhomeland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who We Are And What We Do</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/page/people/</guid>
      <description>By Michael J. Jordan, Visiting Professor, Renmin University of China   Who We Are   We’re 29 enthusiastic Chinese youth, from across China – and one energetic American journalism teacher. For more of our thoughts, please visit the Lessons Learned section.
Meanwhile, our teacher, Michael J. Jordan, is a Beijing-based Communications Consultant, International Educator, Academic Advisor and Storytelling Specialist. Drawing upon the strategies and techniques learned from his two decades as an international journalist, Jordan teaches students how to overcome a core challenge of Strategic Communications: how to effectively reach and impact any smart, curious, global, but non-expert audience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>