<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chinese Feminism on 人大国新班 2016 级</title>
    <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinese-feminism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chinese Feminism on 人大国新班 2016 级</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>国际新闻课程作业</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinese-feminism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amid Two-Child Policy, Working Women Cite New Negative</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/two-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/two-child/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Female graduates were admitted into a job fair 30 minutes earlier than their male counterparts for the first time on March 14 at Renmin, one of China’s top universities, in order to relieve gender discrimination.
In 2016, China abandoned its 39-year-long one-child policy and allowed two children for all couples. The second largest economy now needs more babies to boost its shrinking workforce and to support the ageing population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls’ Day Banners Offer Glimpse of Feminist Awakening</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/girls-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/girls-day/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – March 7, the annual Girls’ Day in China, is traditionally the day when male students state their care or adoration to girls with sugary words on dazzling banners – though, some say for many boys, it’s mere flattery in search of a girlfriend. But this year, some young women at Renmin University of China, at least, chose this occasion to hang some incongruous banners to voice their dissatisfaction with what they see as gender discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>