<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chinese Students on 人大国新班 2016 级</title>
    <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinese-students/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chinese Students on 人大国新班 2016 级</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>国际新闻课程作业</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinese-students/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>As Marketplace Tightens, More Students Drawn To Job Fairs</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/marketplace-tightens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/marketplace-tightens/</guid>
      <description>Job-seekers discuss opportunities with HR staff at Renmin University&amp;#39;s job fairPhoto: Ray Lin
  BEIJING – The biggest-ever job fair, at one of Beijing’s top universities, attracted more than 2,000 job seekers on March 17 — as well as more than 200 recruiters, ranging from manufacturers to Internet companies to government agencies, said the organizer.
“I’ve already submitted three resumes, as I believe the wide net catches more fish,” said Wang Zhijia, who will graduate from Renmin University of China with a degree in economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Students Eye Labor Market, Job Fairs Offer Early Options</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/labor-market/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The biggest-ever job fair of Renmin University of China (RUC), a top university in Beijing, attracted more than 2,000 job seekers on March 17, with more than 200 recruiters, ranging from manufacture to Internet, companies to government agencies, to help graduates in this competitive job-hunting year.
According to the Chinese government, an unprecedented 7.95 million graduate jobhunters will enter the labor market this year, increasing by 300 thousand more than 2016, and the job vacancy amount is growing slowly as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus Contest Aims to Reignite Interest in Book-Reading</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/campus-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/campus-contest/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The Student Union of the Science Department of Renmin University of China (RUC) recently launched a serial book-reading contest every two weeks facing all students on campus primarily aimed at reigniting college students’ awareness on reading and in turn increase their own competitiveness for their future career.
This book-reading contest opens a window onto a broader concern within Chinese educational system, that the Chinese are lagging behind their peers by other countries in terms of reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Chinese Youth, Study-Abroad More Than Just Adventure</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/study-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/study-abroad/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Students poured into international office for interview to participate in studying abroad programs Wednesday morning, which has been one of the most popular programs on campus, as the school staff in charge pointed out.
“Experience in a different culture is attractive,” said Lin, a student who just finished interview, “the idea of meeting and talking with a variety of people all over the world also adds to its weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls’ Day Banners Offer Glimpse of Feminist Awakening</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/girls-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/girls-day/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – March 7, the annual Girls’ Day in China, is traditionally the day when male students state their care or adoration to girls with sugary words on dazzling banners – though, some say for many boys, it’s mere flattery in search of a girlfriend. But this year, some young women at Renmin University of China, at least, chose this occasion to hang some incongruous banners to voice their dissatisfaction with what they see as gender discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Contest Aims to Boost Appeal of Book-Reading</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-contest/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The Student Union of the Science Department of Renmin University recently launched a serial book-reading contest, which is held every two weeks on Wednesday. This contest primarily aims at fellow science students to raise awareness that reading should not only be a burden in their studies, but can be for fun, too, and may even enhance their creativity and competitiveness in the labor market.
Indeed, the book-reading contest opens a window onto a broader concern within Chinese educational system that students are lagging behind their peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Feminists Call for Equality, Spark Controversy</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-feminists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-feminists/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING - At one of China’s leading universities, two feminist students chose the annual Girls’ Day — which typically sees Chinese men express their affection for women — to hang banners and provoke an increasingly sensitive debate: about gender equality.
As men traditionally give little gifts on Girls’ Day, one banner declared: “No Free Gifts from Boys &amp;ndash; I Want Free Rights in Employment!” One of the organizers, who is unwilling to be identified, said: “The call for gender equality should be heard, especially on Girls’ Day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>