<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chinese Culture on 人大国新班 2016 级</title>
    <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinese-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chinese Culture on 人大国新班 2016 级</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rucer.netlify.app/tags/chinese-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothing Exhibit Stirs Chinese Nostalgia – and Cultural Pride</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/clothing-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/clothing-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>Film-makers ask one staffer to explain the aim of their unique exhibit of handmade Chinese clothesPhoto: Michael Li
  BEIJING – A unique, six-month exhibition on handmade Chinese apparel has gained renewed attention at its last stage, as Figure Video, which specializing in cultural celebrities, started shooting a documentary about it at the Backstreet Art-Museum.
Duan Kun, director of the Figure Video team, said that in an era of mass-produced, machine-made clothing, they were interested in the exhibition’s theme: “Seeking Clothes for Stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters Alive Renews Public Passion for Cultural TV Shows</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/letters-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/letters-alive/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – Recently, a “letter reading” TV program called Letters Alive received great popularity and success in China. The director of this program Guan Zhengwen, also a famous producer, gave a lecture to share the secrets behind the huge success of Letters Alive in Renmin University on March 17th.
Letters Alive is a cultural TV program where remarkable letters are read by outstanding performers. Its popularity soared immediately after its first broadcast in Dec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Contest Aims to Boost Appeal of Book-Reading</title>
      <link>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rucer.netlify.app/2017/06/04/university-contest/</guid>
      <description>BEIJING – The Student Union of the Science Department of Renmin University recently launched a serial book-reading contest, which is held every two weeks on Wednesday. This contest primarily aims at fellow science students to raise awareness that reading should not only be a burden in their studies, but can be for fun, too, and may even enhance their creativity and competitiveness in the labor market.
Indeed, the book-reading contest opens a window onto a broader concern within Chinese educational system that students are lagging behind their peers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>